Guide to the Rice University President's Office records, 1968-1969 UA 238
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University President's Office Executive Committee records
1968-1969
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University.
UA 238
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Records of the President's Office Executive Committee, formed in August 1968 by President Pitzer to function after Pitzer's resignation. Includes minutes, memoranda, correspondence, notes, and materials pertaining to the Board of Governors.
Historical Note
The committee consisted of W.E. Gordon, Carey Croneis, Virgil Topazio, and James Sims, and was authorized to act on any matter requiring presidential authority until a new president assumed office. The committee functioned until March 20, 1969 when Frank Vandiver was appointed "Acting President" by the Board of Governors.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of records of the President's Office Executive Committee, formed in August 1968 by President Pitzer to function after Pitzer's resignation. Record include minutes, memoranda, correspondence, notes, and materials pertaining to the Board of Governors. Dates of records span April 1968 - March 1969.
Access Restrictions
Access to this material is restricted. Ask staff at Woodson Research Center (woodson@rice.edu) for assistance obtaining permission from the Office of the President.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
President's Office Executive Committee, primarily W.E. Gordon.
Related Archival Materials
See also: President's Papers, Pitzer and Vandiver/Hackerman for additional materials from this period.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
minutes (administrative records); memorandums; letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Minutes, memos, and correspodence
  - Pre-August 1968 materials, 153681 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, memos, correspondence, etc., Aug.-Sept. 1968; 153682 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, memos, correspondence, etc., Oct. 1968; 153683 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, memos, correspondence, etc., Nov. 1968; 153684 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, memos, correspondence, etc., Dec. 1968; 153685 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, memos, correspondence, etc., Jan. 1969; 153686 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, memos, correspondence, etc., Feb. 1969; 153687 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, memos, correspondence, etc., March 1969; 153688 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous notes, etc., n.d.; 153689 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II: Board of Governors
  - Board of Governors (Gordon), Oct. 1968; 153690 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Governors (Gordon), Nov. 1968; 153691 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board of Governors (Gordon), Dec. 1968; 153692 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board of Governors (Gordon), Jan. 1969; 153693 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board of Governors (Gordon), Feb. 1969; 153694 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Governors (Gordon), March 1969; 153695 (Box 1, Folder 15)